Summary

A motivated, dedicated, and experienced security professional who understands the necessity of protecting people, equipment, property and classified materials. Equally understanding the importance of having good relationships with customers and the public. Fully capable of working both alone and with in a team and comfortable making strategic and critical decisions at a moments notice.

Employment History

Marine Security Guard

Marine Corps Embassy Security Group • Quantico, Virginia

Provide 24 hour armed internal security to an Embassy of the United States, protect classified materials and mission personnel, and assume responsibility of \$100k+ worth of unclassified and classified equipment.

Classified Security Escort

Chipton-Ross, Inc. • El Segundo, California

Provide access and supervision to unclassified personnel to classified spaces and campus facilities. Aided in small jobs for facilities/maintenance to include escorting, cleaning, organizing and sorting room furniture for new purposes.

Professional Skills

- Top Secret Clearance
- Supervisory
- Administrative

- Bilingual
- Leadership Skills
- · Customer Service

Education

High School Diploma

Marine Corps Embassy Security Group • Quantico, Virginia

Trained Marines in the basics of internal armed security with the use of defensive tactics, nonlethal weaponry, and m870 shotgun, m9 service pistol and m4 Carbine.

High School Diploma

Narbonne High School • Los Angeles, California

06/2013

Networking/Cyber Security

Cal State Long Beach Cyber Security Program • Torrance, CA

Currently completing courses/certifications corresponding with networking/cyber security

Languages

• Spanish: Proficient

Work Experience

09/2016 - 07/2019

09/2019 - Present

Graduated

09/2016

Graduated

01/2021

Armed Security Guard (Marine Security Guard) September 2016-July 2019

Mid-Level Manager (U.S. Marine Corps Squad Leader) Bangkok, TH July 2018-Dec 2018

Facilities Coordinator (U.S. Marine Corps Facilities Coordinator) Bangkok, TH Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Logistics/Warehouse Manager (U.S. Marine Corps Supply) Freetown, SL January 2019-July 2019

Supervision

- Supervised, trained and instructed 6 employees in order to sustain them at an operation ready level while maintaining a 100% safety record.
- •Personally inspected the duties and responsibilities of 6 employees receiving a 95% inspection ready rating.
- •Supervised 3 different facilities ensuring they were up to federal safety standards and ensured all areas were kept in working order. (Lights, alarms, bathrooms, floors, etc.)

Customer Service

- •Ensured hundreds of personnel were assisted daily in a highly professional, friendly, and timely manner.
- •Welcomed, sponsored, and trained 4 new hires ensuring they were trained and administratively ready to join the team.
- •Ensured each team member had the required equipment to complete the mission.

Organization

- •Ensured full weekday and weekend shift coverage of 3-5 separate posts while being undermanned.
- •Managed, organized, and accounted for over \$100K worth of supplies detrimental to the mission readiness of the team.
- ·Ensured my duties and responsibilities were met and received a 90% inspection ready rating.
- •Ensured all facility jobs were tracked and completed in a timely manner.